PRABHAKAR ACHARAYA

Hyderabad, India

+919703683410 ♦ prabhakaracharaya@gmail.com ♦ linkedin.com/in/prabhakar-acharaya

SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with more than 3.8 years of expertise in Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing (VAPT), Security Automation, Azure Administration, and Release Management, specializing in identifying and mitigating security risks while optimizing system performance and security processes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Packaged App Development Analyst, System Engineer Accenture

July 2021 - Present Hyderabad

- Identified and remediated 500+ critical security vulnerabilities on Azure-hosted virtual machines, using insights from Splunk and Qualys to implement targeted fixes and strengthen system security.
- Expert in Azure Administration, DevOps CI/CD, and Security Automation, achieving 80% on-time deployments and a 90% reduction in security incidents through optimized processes and effective threat management.
- Developed 5+ security automation tools using PowerShell and Bash, streamlining server security audits and reducing manual effort by 80%, resulting in a significant boost in team efficiency and faster vulnerability assessments.

Cyber Security Intern Trainee

Apr 2020 - Jul 2020 Visakhapatnam, AP

Supraja Technologies

- Simulated DDoS attacks and defaced 2 web servers, reporting the issues to the owners.
- Exploited SQL injection on 5 web app servers and reported the vulnerabilities to the owners.
- Spearheaded a total of 12+ exploitable vulnerabilities through robust usage of specialized PenTest tools on diverse platforms including cloud services; provided actionable insights that led to immediate risk mitigations enhancing data integrity.
- Analyzed web application security risks using OWASP Top 10 benchmarks; streamlined security protocols that equipped the team to mitigate 20+ vulnerabilities, leading to improved compliance and reduced incident response times.
- Engaged in hands-on penetration testing activities using advanced tools such as Kali Linux; Worked on critical vulnerabilities across 4 distinct platforms including web apps, mobile devices, and enterprise Windows installations.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science, Centurion University of Technology and Management - 81.14% 2017 - 2021

SKILLS

Automation & Scripting	PowerShell, Bash, Yaml, Python
Web Application Penetration Testing	Proficient in OWASP Top 10, NetSparker, Burp Suite, NMAP,
	Kali Linux, SQLMAP, SAST and Checkmarx.
ADI Ponetration Testing	Skilled in OWASP API Top 10 Postman and Burn Suite for

API Penetration Testing Skilled in OWASP API Top 10, Postman, and Burp Suite for REST/SOAP web service security assessments.

Cloud Security Experience with Azure Administration, Qualys and Azure Sentinel, along with vulnerability management, and automated patching.

Mobile Application Penetration Testing Experienced in Mobile OWASP Top 10, JADX, MOBSF, apktool, adb, Xposed, Genymotion, Frida, Objection, Cydia, 3uTools, Uncover, Filza, Evil penguin, SSL killswitch

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

- Received multiple appreciations from leadership for developing a security automation tools and delivering presentations.
- Discovered and exploited vulnerabilities in 6 web applications, gained database access, reported findings to the organizations, and secured a free internship offer from Octofor Security.
- Received the Golden Presentation Award for an outstanding presentation on a cybersecurity topic, showcasing effective communication and expertise.